Guide to the Harold and Dorothy Seymour papers, 1830-2016
Seymour, Harold and Dorothy papers, 1830-2016
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Harold and Dorothy Seymour papers, 1830-2016
4809
Harold and Dorothy Seymour
71.1 cubic ft.
Manuscripts, photographs, electronic media, books.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Correspondence, publicity, books, notes, photographs, computer disks, and other documents and records pertaining to the history of baseball and personal papers pertaining to the Seymour family. Also, files of Dorothy Jane (Seymour) Mills relating to her books, A Woman's Work, The Labyrinth, The Scepter, Meatless Meat, and various children's titles.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
Harold Seymour was a baseball scholar and author, Cornell University Ph.D. Class of 1956.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Correspondence, publicity, books, notes, photographs, computer disks, and other documents and records pertaining to the history of baseball and personal papers pertaining to the Seymour family.
Also, files of Dorothy Jane (Seymour) Mills relating to her books, A Woman's Work, The Labyrinth, The Scepter, Meatless Meat, and various children's titles.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Seymour, Harold.; Seymour family.; Seymour, Dorothy Z.; Mills, Dorothy Jane.
Subjects:
Baseball--History.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
CONTAINER LIST
- Correspondence, 1983-1992 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Correspondence, 1990-1992 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Correspondence, 1971-1992 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Blacks, 1978-1984 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Colleges, 1956-1988 (Box 1, Folder 5-6)
- Companies Correspondence - Baseball Organization and Miscellaneous (Box 1, Folder 7-8)
- Cooperstown, 1962-1990 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Copyright, 1959-1965 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Drew, publicity about, 1956-1980 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Allen, Lee, 1955-1960 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Finlay v. Kuhn, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Giamatti (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Foreign Correspondence, Baseball, 1964-1985 (Box 1, Folder 15-16)
- Gates and Cornell, 1956-1990 (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Government Correspondence, Baseball, 1963-1978 (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Indians, 1982-1987 (Box 1, Folder 19)
- Individuals, A-B, 1956-1990 (Box 1, Folder 20)
- Individuals, C-E, 1947-1990 (Box 1, Folder 21)
- Individuals, F-H, 1960-1990 (Box 1, Folder 22-23)
- Individuals, I-K, 1973-1990 (Box 1, Folder 24)
- Individuals, L-N, 1962-1990 (Box 1, Folder 25-26)
- Individuals, Q-R, 1956-1990 (Box 1, Folder 27-28)
- Individuals, S-T (Box 1, Folder 29-30)
- Individuals, U-Z (Box 1, Folder 31-32)
- Correspondence, Libraries, except New York Public Library (Box 1, Folder 33-35)
- Military (Box 1, Folder 36)
- Murdoch (Box 1, Folder 37)
- Museums, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 38)
- New York Public Library, 1955-1982 (Box 1, Folder 39)
- American History Magazine, 1953-1975 (Box 1, Folder 40)
- Corbett, 1962 (Box 1, Folder 41)
- Diamonds Review, 1957-1966 (Box 1, Folder 42-43)
- Orders, 1979-1987 (Box 1, Folder 44-45)
- Organized Baseball, 1946-1983 (Box 1, Folder 46)
- Oxford University Press 1, 1963-1972 (Box 1, Folder 47)
- Oxford University Press 2, 1957-1971 (Box 1, Folder 48)
- Oxford University Press 4, 1969-1987 (Box 1, Folder 49-50)
- Oxford University Press 5, 1984-1990 (Box 1, Folder 51-52)
- Religion, 1977-1984 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Parade Grounds and Brooklyn, 1986-1989 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Overfield, Joseph, 1956-1990 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Prisons, 1978-1984 (Box 2, Folder 4-5)
- Schools, 1978-1987 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Signatures - Sold, 1978 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Soolman, 1973-1974 (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Sporting News, 1956-1983 (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Thorn, 1985 (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Women, 1986-1987 (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Young Correspondence, 1933-1961 (Box 2, Folder 12-13)
- Attendance Figures and Chart (Box 2, Folder 14)
- A (Box 2, Folder 15-17)
- B (Box 2, Folder 18-25)
- C (Box 2, Folder 26-30)
- Cobb Articles (Box 2, Folder 31)
- Cleveland Baseball (Box 2, Folder 32)
- D (Box 2, Folder 33-36)
- Earlier Volumes - Notes to File (Box 2, Folder 37)
- E (Box 2, Folder 38)
- Ervin Hearings (Box 2, Folder 39-40)
- F (Box 2, Folder 41-42)
- F (Box 3, Folder 1-2)
- G (Box 3, Folder 3-4)
- H (Box 3, Folder 5-11)
- I (Box 3, Folder 12-13)
- K (Box 3, Folder 15-17)
- Leisure - old notes (Box 3, Folder 18)
- L (Box 3, Folder 19-22)
- M (Box 3, Folder 23-27)
- Mass Media: Early Outings (Box 3, Folder 28)
- N (Box 3, Folder 29-30)
- Newspaper clippings (Box 3, Folder 31-33)
- O (Box 3, Folder 34-36)
- Outlines - Vol. 2 (Box 3, Folder 37-38)
- P (Box 3, Folder 39-40)
- P (Box 4, Folder 1-2)
- Q (Box 4, Folder 3)
- Rader ms. (Box 4, Folder 4-6)
- R (Box 4, Folder 7-10)
- Relations of 45 top corporations of 1960's with Baseball (Box 4, Folder 11-12)
- Smollar (Box 4, Folder 13)
- Seton Hall (Box 4, Folder 14)
- Standish, Burt L. (Tip Top Weekly) (Box 4, Folder 15)
- S (Box 4, Folder 16-22)
- T (Box 4, Folder 23-24)
- U (Box 4, Folder 25)
- V (Box 4, Folder 26)
- W (Box 4, Folder 27)
- State of Wisconsin vs. Milwaukee Braves, Inc., 1966 (Box 4, Folder 28-31)
- Black (Box 4, Folder 32)
- Frontispiece (Box 4, Folder 33)
- Mount Holyoke (Box 4, Folder 34)
- [photos missing?] (Box 4, Folder 35)
- Photographs (Box 4, Folder 36)
- Miscellaneous Illustrations (Box 4, Folder 37-38)
- Illustrations - Prisons (Box 4, Folder 39)
- Illustrations - Boys (Box 4, Folder 40)
- Illustrations - 4 Military Chapters (Box 4, Folder 41)
- Illustrations - College (Box 4, Folder 42)
- Illustrations - Industrial (Box 5, Folder 1)
- Drew University Trust (Box 5, Folder 2)
- Illustrations - Town Teams (Box 5, Folder 3)
- Illustrations - Semipro (Box 5, Folder 4)
- Illustrations - Women (Box 5, Folder 5)
- Illustrations (Box 5, Folder 6)
- Illustrations - No reply or not available (Box 5, Folder 7-8)
- Illustrations - A-E (Box 5, Folder 9)
- Miscellaneous for Ken Burns (Box 5, Folder 10)
- Vol 4 pix for Ken Burns (Box 5, Folder 11)
- Illustration Ideas (borrowed pix) (Box 5, Folder 12)
- Illustrated Ideas (Box 5, Folder 13-14)
- 100 Years of National League Baseball (Box 5, Folder 15)
- Illustrations (Box 5, Folder 16)
- Vol 3 pix for Ken Burns (Box 5, Folder 17)
- Illustrations Available (Box 5, Folder 18-19)
- R (Box 5, Folder 20)
- W (Box 5, Folder 21-25)
- X,Y,Z (Box 5, Folder 26)
- Source File (Box 5, Folder 27-28)
- Toporcer 2 (Box 5, Folder 29-30)
- Chapter 7 - Great Revolt (Box 5, Folder 31)
- Waseda (Box 5, Folder 32)
- Coca-Cola (Box 5, Folder 33)
- White Auto (Box 5, Folder 34)
- Chadwick, Lester: Baseball Joe Series Ad (Box 5, Folder 35)
- Illustrations (Box 5, Folder 36)
- Detroit Book Preface (Box 5, Folder 37)
- Cleveland Speech Publicity (Box 5, Folder 38)
- Cooperstown Speech (Box 5, Folder 39)
- Drew Program (Box 5, Folder 40)
- Curry Eugene (Box 5, Folder 41)
- Publicity (Box 5, Folder 42-43)
- Drew Publicity (Box 5, Folder 44)
- Cooperstown symposium, June 1990 (Box 5, Folder 45-46)
- Transparencies (Box 5, Folder 47)
- North American Society for Sport History (NASSH) Book Award (Box 5, Folder 48)
- Cornell (Box 5, Folder 49)
- Cleveland Speech (Box 5, Folder 50)
- Vol 3 Paperback (Box 5, Folder 51)
- League Rules and Regulations, City of Milwaukee (Box 5, Folder 52)
- Drew Award, 1990 (Box 6, Folder 1)
- Publicity, 1991 (Box 6, Folder 2)
- Cleveland Travel Bill (Box 6, Folder 3)
- Globe article on opening of season (Box 6, Folder 4)
- Correspondence: National Pastime - Thorn reprint of Leisure Weekly interview (Box 6, Folder 5)
- Toporcer (Box 6, Folder 6-8)
- New York Publicity (Box 6, Folder 9)
- Dorothy Seymour letter to editor (Box 6, Folder 10)
- Batboy (Box 6, Folder 11)
- Ms. review - Hardy ms. (Box 6, Folder 12)
- How Baseball Began (Box 6, Folder 13)
- Jefferson Encyclopedia (Box 6, Folder 14)
- Journal of Higher Education (Box 6, Folder 15)
- Lucas and Smith Saga review (Box 6, Folder 16)
- Oxford Companion (Box 6, Folder 17-18)
- Rickey article (Box 6, Folder 19)
- Smelser review (Box 6, Folder 20)
- Simons (Box 6, Folder 21)
- Vatalaro (Box 6, Folder 22)
- Voigt (Box 6, Folder 23)
- Ball, Bat, and Bar (Box 6, Folder 24)
- Best Articles and Stories (Box 6, Folder 25)
- Brashler review (Box 6, Folder 26)
- Call Me Doctor - Correspondence (Box 6, Folder 27)
- Ward (Box 6, Folder 28)
- Babe Ruth article (Box 6, Folder 29)
- Chambers's Encyclopedia (Box 6, Folder 30)
- Garraty review (Box 6, Folder 31)
- Griffith article for DAB (Box 6, Folder 32)
- Harry Wright article and responses (Box 6, Folder 33)
- Alexander article (Box 6, Folder 34-35)
- National Pastime article - "Books Before Baseball" (Box 6, Folder 36)
- Books Before Baseball, clippings about college sports (Box 6, Folder 37)
- Book review of Murdoch (Ban Johnson) and Alexander (Cobb) (Box 6, Folder 38)
- Beer article (Box 6, Folder 39)
- Speeches (Box 6, Folder 40-42)
- The Scholar as Writer (Box 6, Folder 43)
- Sports History Course Idea (Box 6, Folder 44)
- Ideas for articles (Box 6, Folder 45)
- Ideas for education articles (Box 6, Folder 46)
- Recording idea (Box 6, Folder 47)
- Ideas and notes for an article on Johnson, Ban (Box 6, Folder 48-49)
- Publicity (Box 6, Folder 50)
- Drew (Box 6, Folder 51-52)
- Baseball Awards (Box 6, Folder 53)
- Batboy Correspondence with Sports Heritage (Box 6, Folder 54)
- Publicity - London Times article (Box 7, Folder 1)
- Publicity - Paperbacks v1 and v2 (Box 7, Folder 2)
- Vol 1 and 2 paperbacks (Box 7, Folder 3-4)
- Publicity Vol 2 (Box 7, Folder 5-6)
- Oxford ideas on Vol 3 (Box 7, Folder 7)
- Vol 3 reviews (Box 7, Folder 8)
- Vol 3 publicity (Box 7, Folder 9-10)
- Globe interview and pix (Box 7, Folder 11)
- Baseball cards (Box 7, Folder 12)
- National Pastime - Burke interview (Box 7, Folder 13)
- Casey award (Spitball mag) (Box 7, Folder 14)
- Cornell publicity (Box 7, Folder 15)
- Journal of American History (JOAH) review of Kirsch book (Box 7, Folder 16)
- Book review - Diamonds are Forever (Box 7, Folder 17)
- Drew - Batboy article (Box 7, Folder 18)
- Drew (Ken Cole) (Box 7, Folder 19)
- Drew (Box 7, Folder 20)
- Publicity - Drew Alumni Bulletin (Box 7, Folder 21)
- Drew - Achievement Award (Box 7, Folder 22)
- Big League Batboy (Box 7, Folder 23)
- Batboy - Brooklyn Bums (Box 7, Folder 24)
- Batboy (Box 7, Folder 25)
- Publicity Quotes (Box 7, Folder 26)
- Baseball letters from players, '30's (Box 7, Folder 27)
- College Composition (Box 7, Folder 28)
- Publicity (Box 7, Folder 29)
- Cantwell (Box 7, Folder 30)
- The Youth's Companion (posed for Franke) (Box 7, Folder 31)
- Baseball Clips - high school and before (Box 7, Folder 32)
- Baseball Clips - Drew (Box 7, Folder 33)
- Baseball Clips - Falcons, Crestons, etc. (Box 7, Folder 34)
- Directions to Players on Crestons, Falcons, etc. (Box 7, Folder 35)
- Early articles on current events (Box 7, Folder 36)
- Ph.D. (Box 7, Folder 37)
- Publicity on Ph.D. thesis (Box 7, Folder 38)
- Clips on Seymour's players - Lohrman, Boell, etc. (Box 7, Folder 39)
- Publicity clips, Norwich teaching (Box 7, Folder 40)
- The Purple Matmen (Box 7, Folder 41)
- Publicity - Fenn (Box 7, Folder 42)
- Publicity, Finch news (Box 7, Folder 43)
- Better Business Bureau (Box 7, Folder 44-46)
- Publicity - Mills College (Box 7, Folder 47)
- Publicity on Education (Box 7, Folder 48)
- Publicity Publicity on speeches, Miscellaneous (Box 7, Folder 49)
- Buyer Beware (Box 7, Folder 50)
- Publicity - North Shore Community College (NSCC) (Box 7, Folder 51)
- Baseball Radio Program Idea (Box 7, Folder 52)
- Orange County Community College (OCCC) (Box 7, Folder 53)
- Publicity - University of Buffalo (Box 7, Folder 54)
- Publicity - Social (Box 7, Folder 55)
- Publicity, Radio-TV on articles, Baseball (Box 7, Folder 56)
- Publicity on articles, Education (Box 7, Folder 57)
- Publicity on Articles, Baseball (Box 7, Folder 58)
- Articles, Education (Box 7, Folder 59)
- Commencement Programs (Box 7, Folder 60)
- Publicity ideas, vol. 1 (Box 7, Folder 61)
- Publicity, vol. 1 (Box 7, Folder 62)
- Irish (Box 7, Folder 63)
- Publicity, 1986 (Box 7, Folder 64)
- Publicity (Box 7, Folder 65)
- Reviews (Box 7, Folder 66)
- 5x8 notecards (Box 8)
- Reviews, Publicity (Box 8, Folder 1)
- Publicity, Vol. 1 (Box 8, Folder 2-3)
- Publicity Ideas, Vol. 2 (Box 8, Folder 4-8)
- Keene Sentinel - HS Story (Box 8, Folder 9)
- Autobiographical - youth notes, list of persons (Box 8, Folder 10)
- Autobiographical - chronology (Box 8, Folder 11)
- Autobiographical - pre-school (Box 8, Folder 12)
- Autobiographical - school age (Box 8, Folder 13)
- Autobiographical - kid baseball teams (Box 8, Folder 14)
- Autobiographical - waterfront (Box 8, Folder 15)
- Autobiographical - 1950's (Box 8, Folder 16)
- Drew and Nos [Nostalgia] Correspondence (Box 8, Folder 17-18)
- Ireland - 1970's (Box 8, Folder 19)
- 1980's (Box 8, Folder 20)
- Teaching (Box 8, Folder 21)
- Cornell and Oxford (Box 8, Folder 22)
- Nostalgia book - South and Marriage (divorce papers) (Box 8, Folder 23-26)
- transcript of Testimony, in re-investigation of Kavanaugh Charges, National Board of Arbitration, 1905 (Box 8, Folder 27)
- Game on the Field 1 [5x8 notecards], 1930's (Box 9)
- Toronto Bluejays signed 2000 Honda Hit, Run, Throw, baseball (commercially distributed), MU-1239 (Box 9)
- Game on the Field 2 [Research notes for Volume 4, which was in preparation but never published], 1930's (Box 10)
- Majors Clubs [Volume 4], 1930's (Box 11)
- Majors Leagues [Volume 4], 1930's (Box 12)
- Minors [Volume 4], 1930's (Box 13)
- Players [Volume 4], 1930's (Box 14)
- Mystique 1 [Volume 4], n. d. (Box 15)
- Mystique 2 [Volume 4], n. d. (Box 16)
- Mystique [Volume 4], n. d. (Box 17)
- Player - 1 [Volume 4], n. d. (Box 18)
- Player - 2 [Volume 4], n. d. (Box 19)
- Player Relations - 1 [Volume 4], n. d. (Box 20)
- Player Relations [Volume 4], n. d. (Box 21)
- Game on the Field - 1 [Volume 4], n. d. (Box 22)
- Game on the Field - 2 [Volume 4], n. d. (Box 23)
- Game on the Field - 3 [Volume 4], n. d. (Box 24)
- Clubs and Newspapers [Volume 4] (Box 25)
- League 1 [Volume 4], n. d. (Box 26)
- League 2 [Volume 4], n. d. (Box 27)
- League 3 [Volume 4], n. d. (Box 28)
- Economics [Volume 4], 1940- (Box 29)
- Radio, TV - WWII and After [Volume 4] (Box 30)
- Blacks, V4 [Volume 4], n. d. (Box 31)
- Untitled [Majors] [Volume 4], 1950's (Box 32)
- Add to Muses [Volume 4], n. d. (Box 33)
- Bib Books - Used [Volume 4], n. d. (Box 34)
- Bib Used - Books - 2 [Volume 4], n. d. (Box 35)
- Bib Used Misc. [Volume 4], n. d. (Box 36)
- Bib Mags - 1 [Volume 4], n. d. (Box 37)
- Bib Mags - 2 [Volume 4], n. d. (Box 38)
- New Bib [Volume 4], n. d. (Box 39)
- Research notes for Volume 2 (Box 40)
- Research notes for Volume 1 The Early Years (Box 41-43)
- Research notes for Volume 2 The Golden Age (Box 44-45)
- Research notes for Volume 3 The People's Game (Box 46-50)
- Volume 3 outlines (Box 51-53)
- Foreign research notes (Box 54-55)
- Files/clippings (Box 56-60)
- Seymour personal (Box 61-62)
- SABR and NASSH (Box 63-64)
- Miscellaneous background material and notes for unidentified volumes (Box 65-66)
- Microfilm of "Baseball Digest" (Box 67)
- Congressional hearings, guides (Box 68)
- Books (hardcover) (Box 69-78)
- Books (softcover) (Box 79-81)
- Miscellaneous recent accessions, Includes books, journals, newsletters, correspondence, sports journals, NASSH programs, Jean Ardell article, various clippings and booklets, printed material, biographical notes, Harold Seymour memorial service account; Ken Burns' Florentine Films unused film, eulogy by Tom Heitz, photos of the Harold Seymour ashes-sprinkling at first base, Cooperstown (Box 82-86)
- Stengel - His Life and Times, 1984 (Box 82)
- Baseball in ‘41, 1991 (Box 82)
- Baseball - How to become a player, 1992 (Box 82)
- Megacards, 1993 (Box 82)
- Cardmaster Catalog, 1993 (Box 82)
- Journal of Sport History Vol.20, No.1-2, 1993 (Box 82)
- Sport on Film and Video, 1993 (Box 82)
- Directory of Scholars Identifying with the History of Sport, 1992 (Box 82)
- The National Pastime - A Review of Baseball History, 1993 (Box 82)
- The Baseball Research Journal Vol.22, 1993 (Box 82)
- Membership Directory of Society for American Baseball Research, 1991-1994 (Box 82)
- Baseball Records Update, 1993 (Box 82)
- The SABR Bulletin, 1993-1994 (Box 82)
- A Century of Tiger Greats, 1993 (Box 82)
- Newspaper Clippings (Box 82, Folder 1)
- North American Society for Sport History Proceedings, 1993 (Box 83)
- The National Pastime - A Review of Baseball History, 1994 (Box 83)
- The Baseball Research Journal Vol.23, 1994 (Box 83)
- The SABR Bulletin Vol.25, No.2, 1995 (Box 83)
- Miscellaneous Documents (Box 83, Folder 1)
- Journal of Sports History Vol.20, No. 3, 1993 (Box 83, Folder 2)
- Ken Burns’ "Civil War" (Box 83, Folder 3)
- Society for Sports History/ Society for American Baseball Research (Box 83, Folder 4)
- Scattering of Harold Seymour’s Ashes at Cooperstown (Box 83, Folder 5)
- Harold Seymour Obituaries (Box 83, Folder 6)
- Eulogy for Dr. Harold Seymour and Ceremony at Doubleday Field (Box 83, Folder 7)
- Miscellaneous Baseball/ Sports Publications (Box 83, Folder 8)
- Correspondence (Box 84, Folder 1)
- Correspondence re: Florentine Films (Ken Burns) (Box 84, Folder 2)
- Condolence Letters (Box 84, Folder 3)
- Sales of Sports Memorabilia Collections (Box 84, Folder 4)
- I know what my cat is thinking and it isn't very complimentary, by Dorothy Jane (Seymour) Mills, 2014 (Box 84, Folder 5)
- Miscellaneous Documents (Box 85, Folder 1)
- The National Pastime No.15, 1995 (Box 85)
- Journal of Sports History Vol.21, No.2-3, 1994 (Box 85)
- Saskatchewan Historical Baseball Review, 1991-1992 (Box 85)
- Fan - A Baseball Magazine, 1994 (Box 85)
- Frontline Films Baseball Sync Selects Harold Seymour (Box 85)
- Florentine Films Baseball Sync Seymour Int. (Box 85)
- Miscellaneous Documents (Box 86, Folder 1-5)
- Northern League Media Guide and Record Book, 1996 (Box 86)
- Honus Wagner - The life of Baseball’s "Flying Dutchman", 1996 (Box 86)
- North American Society for Sports History Proceedings, 1995-1996 (Box 86)
- Journal of Sports History Vol.22-23, 1995-1996 (Box 86)
- Saskatchewan Historical Baseball Review, 1993 (Box 86)
- The Sceptre, 1998 (Box 86)
- The Life of Baseball’s First Black Major Leaguer - Fleet Walker’s Divided Heart, 1995 (Box 86)
- Austrians Correspondence Starhamberg/Weitz, Walterdorff, Schiesdrugg, and Habsburgs (Box 87, Folder 1)
- Bib. Used (Box 87, Folder 2)
- Bubenheimer et. al. (Box 87, Folder 3)
- Photos (Box 87, Folder 4)
- Art and Photos etc. - Sceptre Presentation I (Box 87, Folder 5)
- Art and Photos etc. - Sceptre Presentation II (Box 87, Folder 6)
- Sceptre Endorsements (Box 87, Folder 7)
- Biography (Long) (Box 87, Folder 8)
- Heritage (Box 87, Folder 9)
- Irish Connections (Box 87, Folder 10)
- News Releases (Box 87, Folder 11)
- Sceptre Publicity (Box 87, Folder 12)
- Salzburg Festival and Austrians (Box 87, Folder 13)
- Peninsula News Review Interview Sceptre (Box 87, Folder 14)
- Gregory on Sceptre lab (Box 87, Folder 15)
- Austria: Victim or Perpetrator (Box 87, Folder 16)
- Bibliography (Box 87, Folder 17)
- Cast of Characters (Box 87, Folder 18)
- Dinner Menu (Box 87, Folder 19)
- Chapter-by-Chapter Summary (Box 87, Folder 20)
- Outline of Presentation (Box 87, Folder 21)
- Quotations (Box 87, Folder 22)
- Q and A about Austria in 1930’s (Box 87, Folder 23)
- Readers of the Sceptre call the book (Box 87, Folder 24)
- Review of the Sceptre (Box 87, Folder 25)
- Recipes (Box 87, Folder 26)
- Sources (Box 87, Folder 27)
- Study Questions (Box 87, Folder 28)
- Synopsis (Box 87, Folder 29)
- Themes (Box 87, Folder 30)
- What Surprises Readers (Box 87, Folder 31)
- What Readers Say (Box 87, Folder 32)
- Speeches (Box 87, Folder 33)
- Some Sceptre Notes (Box 87, Folder 34)
- Austria (Box 87, Folder 35)
- Irish File (Box 87, Folder 36)
- Ireland 1920’s I (Box 87, Folder 37)
- Ireland 1920’s II (Box 87, Folder 38)
- Cork, Ireland (Box 87, Folder 39)
- Sceptre - Labyrinth (Box 87, Folder 40)
- Sequel - New York (Box 87, Folder 41)
- People: Hitler (Box 87, Folder 42)
- Salzburg I (Box 87, Folder 43)
- Salzburg II (Box 87, Folder 44)
- People: Robbentrap (Box 87, Folder 45)
- People: Starhemburg (Box 87, Folder 46)
- Symbolism (Box 87, Folder 47)
- Salt Mine (Box 87, Folder 48)
- Bibliography (Box 87, Folder 49)
- Austria (Box 87, Folder 50)
- Austria Trip 2000 (Box 87, Folder 51)
- Costumes (Box 87, Folder 52)
- England Trip 2000 (Box 87, Folder 53)
- Europe: Climate 400-600 AD (Box 87, Folder 54)
- Fuschl (Box 87, Folder 55)
- Heritage (Box 87, Folder 56)
- Irish Language (Box 87, Folder 57)
- Irish Prehistory (Box 87, Folder 58)
- Ireland Trip 2000 (Box 87, Folder 59)
- Language (Box 87, Folder 60)
- Language: German, Welsh (Box 87, Folder 61)
- Music (Box 87, Folder 62)
- Cornell Fellowship, 1980-2001 (Box 88, Folder 1)
- Batboy Article, 1988 (Box 88, Folder 2)
- Oxford, 1989-1992 (Box 88, Folder 3)
- Burns, Ken Correspondence, 1990-2002 (Box 88, Folder 4)
- Cooperstown, 1992 (Box 88, Folder 5)
- Bb News, 1992-2000 (Box 88, Folder 6)
- SABR Award, 1993 (Box 88, Folder 7)
- Ardell, Jean Correspondence, 1994-2003 (Box 88, Folder 8)
- Cooperstown Ceremony of Ashes, 1995 (Box 88, Folder 9)
- Cooperstown Memorial, 1995 (Box 88, Folder 10)
- NYPL Spalding Collection, 1998 (Box 88, Folder 11)
- Pictures for Ralph, 2000-2002 (Box 88, Folder 12)
- Women’s Baseball Leg. I, 2000-2003 (Box 88, Folder 13)
- Women’s Baseball Leg. II, 2000-2003 (Box 88, Folder 14)
- Book Review DiMaggio, 2001-2002 (Box 88, Folder 15)
- BB Reliquary + Neighborhood, 2001-2004 (Box 88, Folder 16)
- Ft. Myers Women’s Bb, 2002 (Box 88, Folder 17)
- McFarland, 2002-2004 (Box 88, Folder 18)
- Publicity Responses for A.W.W., 2002-2004 (Box 88, Folder 19)
- Lizzy Murphy, 2003 (Box 88, Folder 20)
- Review of Nathan Saying It’s So, 2003 (Box 88, Folder 21)
- Research Presentation for SABR, 2003 (Box 88, Folder 22)
- Drew U. Magazine "Diamond Scholar", 2003 (Box 88, Folder 23)
- Cunningham, John T., 2003 (Box 88, Folder 24)
- Women’s Baseball Handouts, 2003 (Box 88, Folder 25)
- Award History (Box 88, Folder 26)
- Baseball Topics (Box 88, Folder 27)
- Contacts A-G (Box 88, Folder 28)
- Contacts H-Z (Box 88, Folder 29)
- Harold Seymour (Box 88, Folder 30)
- Westbrook Review (Box 88, Folder 31)
- Ann Likes Red, 2002 (Box 89, Folder 1)
- ALR Fans A-G, 2001-2003 (Box 89, Folder 2)
- ALR Fans H-O, 2001-2003 (Box 89, Folder 3)
- ALR Fans P-Z, 2001-2003 (Box 89, Folder 4)
- Publicity Ann, 2002 (Box 89, Folder 5)
- Who Loves Ann (Box 89, Folder 6)
- Releases Ann, 2001 (Box 89, Folder 7)
- Children’s Books Articles, 2003-2004 (Box 89, Folder 8)
- Return of Ballerina Bess (Box 89, Folder 9)
- Ballerina Bess Quotes (Box 89, Folder 10)
- Trafford New Ed. Ballerina, 2003 (Box 89, Folder 11)
- Ballerina Bess Fan mail, 2002-2003 (Box 89, Folder 12)
- Barnhart & Pitman, 1965-1976 (Box 89, Folder 13)
- The Sandwich Article, 2002 (Box 89, Folder 14)
- The Sandwich, 2003 (Box 89, Folder 15)
- Endorsements/Reviews, 2001-2003 (Box 89, Folder 16)
- Big Beds, 2003 (Box 89, Folder 17)
- Bill and the Fish (Box 89, Folder 18)
- Bookslove, 2001-2002 (Box 89, Folder 19)
- Fans of Grossel Books, 1965-2001 (Box 89, Folder 20)
- The Tent, 2003 (Box 89, Folder 21)
- The Pond, 2002 (Box 89, Folder 22)
- Warwick, 1966-2001 (Box 89, Folder 23)
- PW Publicity, 2001 (Box 89, Folder 24)
- Greenstein Column, 1999 (Box 89, Folder 25)
- MM Releases, 2001-2002 (Box 89, Folder 26)
- Vegetarian, 2003-2004 (Box 89, Folder 27)
- Letters on MM, 2003 (Box 89, Folder 28)
- High School, WRU, and Cleve. State (Box 89, Folder 29)
- Education/Reading Articles, 1967-1970 (Box 89, Folder 30)
- Linguistics Articles, 1969-1999 (Box 89, Folder 31)
- Ireland, 1974 (Box 89, Folder 32)
- Women, 1978 (Box 89, Folder 33)
- Aidan’s Luck, 1986 (Box 89, Folder 34)
- Toad Charts, 1987 (Box 89, Folder 35)
- Articles on Editing, 1989-1990 (Box 89, Folder 36)
- Keene, NH Articles, 1990 (Box 89, Folder 37)
- D.S. Articles, 1991-2003 (Box 89, Folder 38)